Arpit Tripathi

Software Engineer

arpit04tripathi@gmail.com | 9146714272 | LinkedIn/arpit04tripathi | hackerrank.com/arpit04tripathi |

Profile Summary

- A professional Software Developer with 5 years of experience as a Java Backend/Full Stack Developer.
- Software Development using Industry Wide Best Practices like Test Driven Development (TDD), SOLID principles, Object
 Oriented Design (OOD), Design Patterns, Agile Development Methodologies, Clean Code approach, Scrum etc.
- Experience with building and delivering code for multi-branched, multi-module web application to production environment having CI/CD, Gated Deployment with Quality Check stages (SIT and UAT) in matrixed organizations.
- Ability to own multiple streams of work and to organize self to deliver them in a timely fashion while working in self-organizing
 and cross-functional teams.

Skills

Programming and Frameworks : Java 8, Spring Boot, Spring Core, Spring MVC, Angular 8, Typescript, Hibernate

Unit Testing : JUnit, Mockito, Cucumber

Build Tools and Repository : Gradle, Maven, GitLab, GitHub, Tortoise SVN, Jenkins

Cloud Tech : Amazon Web Services (AWS), Micro Service, Apache Kafka, REST API

Database : SQL (MySQL, DB2), **NoSQL** (**DynamoDB**, Cassandra) Additional Tools : **Auth0**, **Swagger**, **Open-API**, **JIRA**, **Eclipse** (**STS**)

Work Experience

Siemens Industry Software Limited (SISW) Software Engineer

Pune, India Sept 2019 – Present

Project : EMN (Electronics Manufacturing Network)

• Actively participating in planning and brainstorming sessions for B2B Solution.

SIEMENS Ingenuity for life

- Partnered with Tech Lead to develop POC (Proof of Concept) with Auth0 and Open API.
- Developing reusable Microservices using API first approach, AWS, Spring Boot and AuthO.
- Writing Unit and Integration Tests for TDD using frameworks like Mockito and Cucumber.
- Actively participate in Scrum Meetings to track progress and mitigate impediments on daily basis.
- Collaborating with Geographically dispersed team members having different days as workweek.

TIAA GBS Analyst (Software Developer) May 2018 - Sept 2019

Project : IA (Immediate Annuities)

• Developing Microservices based on Event Driven Architecture using Apache Kafka.



- Understanding and estimating the required efforts with organizational quality standards during Scale Agile Ceremonies.
- Worked on aggregator microservice communicating with downstream systems critical for the functionality.
- Collaborated with teams and individuals throughout the firm to accomplish common goals of Agile Release train (SAFe).

Cognizant Technology Solutions Prog

Programmer Analyst

Aug 2015 - May 2018

Project : ACARS (Aircraft Communication Addressing and Reporting System)

• Partnering with supporting tech leads to develop realistic and achievable project estimates.



- Developing POC and business specific Microservices based on documents such as Design Document, BRD, Use-Case etc.
- Working with business partners to ensure efforts are focused in the right way to satisfy business needs for the long term.

Project: Warehouse Management System

- Understanding Business Requirements and Designing new modules/functionality to meet those needs.
- Performing Impact Analysis and rendering change requests along with estimating the required efforts.
- Provided developer support for Production issues of modules owned.

Recognitions in Organization

- Rain Maker (2017) for achieving excellent results.
- Diamond in the Rough (2016) for contribution, competency and enthusiastic efforts.

Educational Qualification

Bachelor's DegreeSGSITS (Electronics & Telecommunication)Indore, MP (India)20157.98 (CGPA)Higher SecondaryKendriya Vidyalaya No.1Bhopal, MP (India)201081.4%High SchoolKendriya Vidyalaya No.1Bhopal, MP (India)200883.2%